export var questions = [
  {
    question: "The particle that has the smallest mass is the",
    options: ["Electron", "Proton", "Nucleus", "Ion", "Neutron"],
    answer: "Electron",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The person given credit for developing the first modern periodic table is",
    options: ["Dalton", "Democritus", "Thomson", "Mendeleev", "Chadwick"],
    answer: "Mendeleev",
  },
  {
    question: "Two atoms are isotopes if they have",
    options: [
      "Different atomic numbers",
      "The same mass number, but different atomic numbers",
      "The same number of protons and neutrons",
      "The same number of electrons, but a different number of neutrons",
      "The same atomic number, but a different mass number",
    ],
    answer: "The same atomic number, but a different mass number",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The element found in the periodic table in Group 4 and Period 6 is",
    options: [
      "Halfnium, Hf",
      "Selenium, Se",
      "Gadolinium, Gd",
      "Chromium, Cr",
      "Aluminum, Al",
    ],
    answer: "Halfnium, Hf",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The element found in the periodic table in Group 6 and period 4 is",
    options: [
      "Halfnium, Hf",
      "Selenium, Se",
      "Lithium, Li,",
      "Gadolinium, Gd",
      "Chromium, Cr",
    ],
    answer: "Chromium, Cr",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following matches of group number and common name is incorrect?",
    options: [
      "Group 2 - Alkaline Earth Metals",
      "Group 6 - Lanthanides",
      "Group 1 - Alkali Metals",
      "Group 17 - Halogens",
      "Group 18 - Noble Gases",
    ],
    answer: "Group 6 - Lanthanides",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following matches of group number and common name is incorrect?",
    options: [
      "Group 7 - Transition Metals",
      "Group 2 - Alkali Earth Metals",
      "Group 17 - Halogens",
      "Group 2 - Actinides",
      "Group 18 - Noble Gases",
    ],
    answer: "Group 2 - Actinides",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the periodic law, chemical properties are repeated at a regular interval when",
    options: [
      "Elements are listed in order of their atomic radius",
      "Elements are listed in order of their date of discovery",
      "Families of elements are listed in order",
      "Periods are arranged in order",
      "Elements are arranged in order of increasing atomic number",
    ],
    answer: "Elements are arranged in order of increasing atomic number",
  },
  {
    question: "A metaloid in Period 3 is",
    options: ["Scandium", "Aluminum", "Germanium", "Phosphorus", "Silicon"],
    answer: "Silicon",
  },
  {
    question: "A nonmetal in Period 6 is",
    options: ["Astatine", "Iodine", "Polonium", "Radon", "Rubidum"],
    answer: "Radon",
  },
  {
    question: "The atomic mass of barium is due to the number of",
    options: [
      "Neutrons and electrons in the nucleus",
      "Electrons in the nucleus",
      "Protons and neutrons in the nucleus",
      "Protons and electrons in the atom",
      "Protons in the nucleus",
    ],
    answer: "Protons and neutrons in the nucleus",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The properties of elements repeat periodically if they are arranged by",
    options: [
      "Atomic mass",
      "Atomic charge",
      "Atomic number",
      "Number of neutrons",
      "Number of electrons",
    ],
    answer: "Atomic number",
  },
  {
    question: "The atomic number is the number of",
    options: [
      "Protons in the nucleus",
      "Neutrons in the nucleus",
      "Protons plus the number of neutrons in the nucleus",
      "Electrons plus the number of protons in the nucleus",
      "Electrons plus the number of neutrons in the nucleus",
    ],
    answer: "Protons in the nucleus",
  },
  {
    question: "Why does atomic radius decrease from left to right in a period?",
    options: [
      "Nuclear charge increases from left to right in a period",
      "Nuclear charge decreases from left to right in a period",
      "The number of energy levels increase from left to right in a period",
      "The number of energy levels decreases from left to right in a period",
      "The number of electrons decreases from left to right in a period",
    ],
    answer: "Nuclear charge increases from left to right in a period",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why does electron affinity increase from bottom to top in a chemical family?",
    options: [
      "Nuclear charge increases from bottom to top in a chemical family",
      "Nuclear charge decrease from bottom to top in a chemical family",
      "The number of energy levels increases from bottom to top in a chemical family",
      "The number of energy levels decreases from bottom to top in a chemical family",
      "The number of electrons increases from bottom to top in a chemical family",
    ],
    answer:
      "The number of energy levels decreases from bottom to top in a chemical family",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is the most reactive element?",
    options: ["Helium", "Radon", "Francium", "Hydrogen", "Ununoctium"],
    answer: "Francium",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why is it easier to remove an electron from potassium than it is to remove an electron from calcium?",
    options: [
      "Potassium has a higher electron affinity",
      "Potassium has a higher ionization energy",
      "Potassium has a lower nuclear charge",
      "Calcium has a lower electron affinity",
      "Calcium is a metal, but potassium is not",
    ],
    answer: "Potassium has a lower nuclear charge",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is a practical use of radioisotopes?",
    options: [
      "Determining the age of old objects",
      "Medical diagnosis",
      "Production of electricity",
      "All of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the Lewis model of the atom, the number of bonding electrons in a nitrogen atom is",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "5", "7"],
    answer: "3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following atoms is believed to contain three lone pairs of electrons?",
    options: ["H", "Al", "B", "C", "Cl"],
    answer: "Cl",
  },

  {
    question: "Which of the following is the correct order of dipole moment?",
    options: [
      "BF3 < NH3 < NF3 < H2O",
      "H2O < NF3 < NH3 < BF3",
      "BF3 < NF3 < NH3 < H2O",
      "More than one of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "BF3 < NF3 < NH3 < H2O",
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of the following aqueous solutions will be neutral?",
    options: [
      "NH4Cl",
      "NaCl",
      "KCN",
      "More than one of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "NaCl",
  },
  {
    question: "The acid used in storage batteries",
    options: [
      "sulphuric acid",
      "Nitric acid",
      "formic acid",
      "More than one of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "sulphuric acid",
  },
  {
    question: "Chemical Formula of common salt is ______.",
    options: [
      "NaOH",
      "NaCl",
      "NaOCl",
      "More than one of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "NaCl",
  },
  {
    question: "Chemical name of washing soda is:",
    options: [
      "Sodium chloride",
      "Sodium hydrogen carbonate",
      "Sodium carbonate",
      "Sodium hydroxide",
    ],
    answer: "Sodium carbonate",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is called 'Pearl ash'?",
    options: ["Na2CO3", "NaHCO3", "K2CO3", "CaCO3"],
    answer: "K2CO3",
  },
  {
    question: "Which acid is present in sour milk?",
    options: ["Citric Acid", "Acetic Acid", "Glycolic Acid", "Lactic Acid"],
    answer: "Lactic Acid",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ratio of the mass of hydrogen to the mass of oxygen in water is always ________.",
    options: ["2 : 1", "1 : 8", "8 : 1", "1 : 2"],
    answer: "1 : 8",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many water molecules are present in one molecule of washing soda?",
    options: ["8", "5", "7", "10"],
    answer: "10",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the common name of Mercury Sulfide?",
    options: ["Marsh Gas", "Mohr's Salt", "Potash Alum", "Vermilion"],
    answer: "Vermilion",
  },
  {
    question:
      "CO2 when passed in excess, in lime water turns colourless again because of:",
    options: [
      "Calcium Carbonate",
      "Calcium bicarbonate",
      "Calcium Chloride",
      "Copper Carbonate",
    ],
    answer: "Calcium bicarbonate",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To which category of reactions does the following chemical reaction belong?\nNaCl(aq) + AgNO3(aq) â†’ NaNO3(aq) + AgCl(s)",
    options: [
      "Double displacement reaction",
      "Redox reaction",
      "Displacement reaction",
      "Combination reaction",
    ],
    answer: "Double displacement reaction",
  },
  {
    question: "What is pH of Lemon Juice?",
    options: ["3.8", "5.5", "6.6", "2.5"],
    answer: "2.5",
  },
];
